Hey, what's up everyone? My name is Tim. In this video I'm gonna explain how
you can easily convert audio, so let's say a voice recording or a podcast
to subtitles. And as a bonus, at the end of the video I'm showing you
how you can use one of our templates and make amazing videos with subtitles
with one of our templates. So stay tuned. So in this video we're
to use VEED's online video editor and you can instantly get started.
Simply head over to your browser and type in the URL box, edit new
and click on Enter. You can also click on the first link in the description.
Now we're in V's editor and we can get started. You can upload an audio
or video file if you like. You can choose one of the templates, but for
now I'm just going to convert audio to subtitles. So I'm going to click on
upload a file, select the audio file I want to convert to subtitles
and click on open again. We're prompted to choose a template or
a dimension, but I just want to start with a blank canvas. So I'm going
to click on start with a blank canvas and as you can see. Hey everyone,
my name is Tim. I just wanted to say a quick hi to. The audio
file is imported, so now I want to turn this audio fragment to subtitles
and we're going to use VEED's automatic transcription tool. So to get started it's
very easy. Head over to subtitles in the left menu and then choose one of
the subtitle options. You can choose to add subtitles manually or
you can choose the auto subtitle tool. In this case we're going to choose auto
subtitle. Now we're prompted to choose the language we spoke in our video.
And as you can see there's a lot of languages you can choose from.
In this case, I chose to speak English, so I can only do two languages
anyway. So I'm going to select English and then click
on start. And now the auto transcription tool will automatically transcribe
the audio to text and turn them into subtitles. And as you
can see we converted audio to subtitles and we can watch it back.
I just wanted to say a quick hi to everyone and I hope you're all
doing well. Nice. In a bit I'm going to download these subtitles as
a text file and an SRT file. But first I want to show you how
you can edit these subtitles. So on the left you can see all the text
boxes, they're all synced with the video itself as you can also see in
the bottom timeline. But let's say you want to change the text,
you can just simply click on the text itself and just change whatever
you like. Because we use the auto transcription tool, it's already very accurate so I
don't need to change much. But let's say you want to change the timing of
the subtitles. Simply head over to the bottom timeline and you can click and drag
on one of the sides. Or just simply click from the middle and just
move it around. As you can see on the bottom timeline you can also add
subtitles or you can split subtitles. For instance if you're going to use
the play ad in the bottom timeline and just let it rest somewhere. And we're
going to click on split subtitle and then split the subtitle Tada
into. So that's how you edit your subtitles. So if you want to download your
subtitles as a text file, srt file or vtt file,
simply head over to options in the subtitles menu. And on the download
subtitles you can choose one of the formats, SRT, VTT or text.
In this case I'm going to choose SRT and I'm going to click on the
download button and I also want to download a text file from it. So again,
just choose the format, click on text format and click on the
download button. Now if we take a look in our downloads
folder, you can see the SRT file and the text file. We can open a
text file for instance. And as you can see all the transcriptions are in there.
Now let's say you want to do more. Let's say you want to turn this
audio fragment into a video with subtitles in there.
We simply go back to the beginning. You can choose one of the templates for
instance. And once you chose one of the templates, you can easily change any
element that you can see in the video frame. And as I showed you
before, you can easily use the auto transcription tool to turn the audio to
subtitles again. And now with the help of Vit's editor, you can edit the audio
visualizers, the text, the subtitles. You can customize them,
design them, you can change the background, add images, add music,
whatever you like. And then if you did all that,
just simply click on the export button in the right top corner and make
sure burn subtitles is enabled because that's what makes the subtitles
burned into the video. And then when the video is rendered you're free to choose
to share your video with your friends, colleagues or family. All right?
And that's how you convert audio to subtitles. Thank you so much for watching.
Good luck and have a nice day.